# Elijah Rutschman

http://github.com/elijahr :: elijahr@gmail.com :: (773) 814-5185 :: 5050 N. Bernard, Chicago, IL 60625

### Summary

Web developer, architect, tinkerer. I'm pragmatic, a polyglot, but with heavy expertise in Python, JavaScript and CSS.

I'm currently hacking on Web and mobile social video apps for Switchcam.

I cut my teeth at a fast-paced development studio, worked at a few start-ups, and before that managed Linux servers. I've worn many hats and solved many problems in the 6 years I've worked in the field.

I hold a Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Science and Philosophy from Northeastern Illinois University in Chicago.

#### Skills

Python JavaScript / CoffeeScript PhoneGap / Cordova Django Backbone.js Celery **iQuery** С UNIX HTML 5 / CSS 3 Cython RESTful API design Responsive layouts PHP SQL **Photoshop** CakePHP

### Experience

Switchcam Software Engineer, Chicago / San Francisco, 09/2012 - Present

Full-stack Web and mobile development at a social video start-up.

- I led the API design, back-end, and front-end development for Switchcam Director, a cutting-edge social video platform.
- I led the prototyping of Switchcam's second generation video-capture mobile app and API using Twitter Bootstrap, PhoneGap and Ember.js.
- I delivered Switchcam Agent, a platform for aggregating social content from real-world events and garnering attention analytics. I collaborated on back-end development and owned front-end development.

Key skills and technologies used: RESTful API design, Python/Django, Celery, Backbone.js, Ember.js, PhoneGap, and Twitter Bootstrap.

# Sanders New Media Lead Django Developer, Chicago, 03/2011 - 09/2012

Full-stack Web development at a development studio. I worked with a small team on several projects at any given time. My responsibilities included being the primary engineering contact for some of our larger clients as well as managing other developers.

- I developed an e-commerce platform to replace an existing WordPress-based site that enabled a popular start-up apparel company to scale as their business grew.
- I developed highly visible Facebook apps (games and promotions) for a variety of large brands that allowed them to significantly increase their fan engagement.
- I owned development of Stratus, a heavily customized CMS based on Django's admin app, used by most of our clients.

Key skills and technologies used: Python/Django, Celery, Backbone.js, Twitter Bootstrap, Cocoa/Objective-C, Adobe Flex, and CakePHP.

Hagerty Consulting Software Engineer, Evanston, 06/2009 - 03/2011

Front-end and back-end development at a business services start-up. I worked with a small team on Perfolio, a Web application for managing client feedback.

- I fixed bugs and implemented new front-end and back-end features.
- I migrated the platform from Windows to Linux servers.
- I converted the app to a "hashbang" URL scheme for faster browsing.
- I improved ease of navigation through large sets of data in the app via AJAX-based "omnibox" style search.

Key skills and technologies used: JavaScript/jQuery, Python/Django.

#### MSDSonline Software Engineer, Chicago, 01/2008 - 06/2009

Front-end, back-end, and Windows app development at a business services company in the Health and Safety sector.

I worked with a medium-sized team on products for managing inventory of Material Safety Data Sheets.

I mostly worked on maintaining existing Web and desktop software and fixing bugs, but I also delivered:

- AJAX-based search of MSDSs to improve usability.
- A standards-based JavaScript utility library written from scratch to provide a solid framework for new AJAX-heavy products.

Key skills and technologies used: JavaScript, VB.NET, SQL.

### MSDSonline / SpringCM IT Engineer, Chicago, 06/2006 - 12/2007

I managed Windows and Linux servers, responded to helpdesk tickets, and provisioned desktops and laptops for new employees.

#### Education

## Northeastern Illinois University Chicago

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science, Philosophy 2004 - 2008

Honors: Dean's List (for maintaining a 3.75 or higher GPA)

# Antioch College Yellow Springs, OH

Creative Writing 2002 - 2004